James David Finch.

Product Support Engineer & Frontend Developer

Hey, my name is James David Finch, i'm a versatile and self-taught IT professional with extensive experience across multiple sectors. From web development to cyber security and IT support, I have a broad skill set and passion for learning make me a valuable asset to any team.

Work Experience

Front-End Web Developer @DestinationCore

December 2020 - August 2022

- Developed dynamic, modular websites for shopping centers and districts throughout the United Kingdom, using responsive layouts and clean, efficient code.
- Spearheaded the development of a base repository and folder structure that served as the foundation for all projects, streamlining workflows and increasing team efficiency.
- Mentored and trained new team members, sharing best practices and advancing the team's overall knowledge and confidence in our products.
- Reviewed and contributed to pull requests and workflows across multiple repositories, ensuring code quality and maintainability.

IT Support Technician & Web Developer @Town Close

May 2015 - January 2019

- Collaborated on the development of a holiday program booking website, using Sage Pay payment integration to enable families to easily book and pay for their children's attendance.
- Cultivated strong interpersonal skills while providing effective support to a diverse range of users across different generations.
- Thrived in a high-pressure environment, providing essential technical support to teachers and staff, ensuring that their needs were met and issues resolved in a timely and efficient manner.
- Managed over 300 Windows users, utilizing Active Directory and other Microsoft products to provide effective moderation and troubleshooting services.

Founder & Lead Developer @NexusNation

August 2013 - June 2021

- Developed and managed bespoke online game servers that served over 1.5 million unique users, providing a unique gaming experience and fostering a loyal community.
- Built a custom administration panel and statistics system that allowed the staff team to easily maintain the servers and track their performance, even when working remotely.
- Managed a team of 20 staff members, developing strong leadership and hospitality skills while ensuring that the team was meeting its goals and targets.
- Gained valuable experience with Unix systems, configuring firewalls to protect against Layer7 attacks and ensuring the security and stability of the servers.

Education

- BSc @ UCLAN 2019 - 2020
- **L3 Diploma @ CCN** 2015 - 2017
- L2 Diploma @ CCN
 2014 2015
- GCSE @ WyHigh Ac 2009 - 2014

Skills

Front-End Development

Back-End Development

Cloud Computing

Unix Systems

Contact Info

🔀 cv@jdf.gg

jdf.gg